Guide to the George and Katy Abraham Papers, 1915-2005
Abraham, George and Katy papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George and Katy Abraham Papers, 1915-2005.
6777
George, Abraham 1915-
14.3 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Manuscripts, Photographs, Printed Materials, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers of George and Katy Abraham including notes, correspondence showing life in the military in Africa during World War II.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
George "Doc" Abraham (Cornell Class of 1939) and Katherine "Katy" Mehlenbacher Abraham (Cornell Class of 1943) married on July 4, 1942, just before Doc shipped out with Task Force 5889, one of the U.S. Army's first integrated units, to safeguard Liberia's rubber plantations during World War II. Doc's parents were Lebanese immigrants. Katy dropped out of Cornell to work as a munitions inspector. She finished her degree after raising their two children, Leanna and Darryl, and actually graduated from Cornell in 1969. Katy and Doc operated a commercial greenhouse and florist shop, offered landscape architectural services, published nine books on gardening, and worked to extend the reach of their "Green Thumb" garden column. Doc also wrote "The belles of Shangri-La: and other stories of sex, snakes, and survival from World War II," published in 2000. Doc died on January 27, 2005 and Katy on May 25, 2005.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers documenting the lives of Doc and Katy Abraham, including correspondence, clippings, notes on articles and "Belles of Shangri-La," manuscripts and articles, documents, spent shells and dog tags, Doc's photographs recording images from West and North Africa (Ghana or the Gold Coast, Egypt, Eritrea, Ethiopia, Liberia, Nigeria, and North Africa), and U.S. involvement there during World War II including Africans at work, daily life, and dancing; animals including chimpanzees, baboons, monkeys, giraffes, dogs, cattle, donkeys, snakes, vultures; soldiers; landmarks; military training, equipment, and repair; medical conditions and treatments including malaria, elephantiasis, filariasis, steatopygia, leprosy, and snakebite. (The descriptions of the photographs were largely supplied by Doc.) Also included are books relating to the war, tribal markings, airlines, Liberia, tribes, tribal medicine, geography, photography, and Africa as well as unidentified films about Africa and films labelled Africa 1943-1944, Accra, and Red Sea. Also, their horticultural work and garden advice that appeared in newspapers, radio, and television under the title "The Green Thumb" from 1960-1999, many of which are in the form of clippings, articles and their regular newspaper columns. Also correspondence 1979-1980's, teaching materials, thanks you letters, awards, agreements and contracts, subject files, radio program scripts and book reviews. The collection also contains a small amount of personal material, such as a file of their obituaries and memorials and a scrapbook containing Doc's Cornell diploma and clippings regarding Leanna's marriage.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Abraham, George,1915-; Abraham, Katy.; United States.Army--African American troops--History--20th century.
Subjects:
Medicine--Africa--W orld War, 1939-1945.; Gardening.; Lebanese Americans.; World War, 1939-1945--African Americans.
Places:
Africa--History--20th century.; Liberia--History--20th century.; Egypt; Eritrea; Ethiopia; Ghana; Liberia; Nigeria
Form and Genre Terms:
Home movies.; Photographs.; Radio scripts.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Africa
Boxes: 1-7
Subseries I.a. Correspondence, Clippings and Memorabilia
Subseries I.b. Belles of Shangri-La files
Subseries I.c. Photographs
Subseries I.d. Photo Negatives
Subseries I.e. Books
Subseries I.f. Films
Subseries I.g. CDs
Subseries I.h. DVDs
Series II. Gardening
Boxes: 8-22
Subseries II.a. Clippings, correspondence, photos and slides, Green Thumb articles, and personal files
Subseries II.b. Green Thumb subject files, alphabetical
Subseries II.c. Personal, Green Thumb, and gardening videotapes
Subseries II.d. Green Thumb and gardening CDs
Subseries II.e. Green Thumb and gardening DVDs
Subseries II.f. Audio tapes
Subseries II.g. Negatives: non-African
Subseries II.h. Oversize and miscellaneous personal materials
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Africa
  - Correspondence, Clippings and Memorabilia
    - Letters from Doc to Katy, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Letters from Doc to Katy, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letters from Doc to Katy, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Poem in shape of Africa (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Yank Magazine article, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Military attempt at integration (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Letter to Doc about writing book about fighting malaria (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Misc. World War II articles (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Treatise on jungle combat and article on North Africa army prison (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Misc. clippings sent to Katy by Doc, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Spent shells and dog tags sent to Doc by VFW, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Army publications to which Doc contributed (sent to Katy) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Belles of Shangri-La files
    - "Belles of Shangri-La" manuscript (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Original notes (detailed) for "Belles of Shangri-La" (Box 1, Folder 15-18)
    - Correspondence and articles regarding History Channel show, Sex in World War II, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - First drafts of stories for "Belles of Shangri-La" (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Research and notes for "Belles of Shangri-La" (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Belles of Shangri-La" manuscript with editing notes (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Original captions for photos in "Belles of Shangri-La" (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "World War II: The War in Africa" by Doc Abraham, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - "Belles of Shangri-La" manuscripts (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
    - Copies of photos with captions for "Belles of Shangri-La" (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "Belles of Shangri-La" manuscript with Katy's notes (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Newspaper articles regarding the publication of "Belles of Shangri-La" (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Photographs
    - George "Doc" Abraham (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Four soldiers (Doc second from left) (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Doc and chimpanzee (Billy O) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Baboon, chimp fighting with dog (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Billy O with pipe, vultures with dog (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Billy O chimpanzee Christmas card (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Chimpanzee (small) (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Africans pouring fuel, chimp Billy O (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Chimp Billy O with basketball, building with guard (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Men using mill, Billy O, sphinx, old pyramid, street merchant (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Black maned baboon (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Chimp on jeep, military airplane loading, outside theater (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Chimp Billy O with pipe (Box 1, Folder 42-43)
    - Doc with chimp (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Chimp Billy O with basketball (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Chimp Billy O (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Chimp Billy O with pipe (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Chimp Billy O (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Billy O with Pepsodent tooth powder (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Billy O, man with enlarged scrotum (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Chimpanzee on military jeep (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - American cuts chimpanzee's hair (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Street scene with army tank, transports, car, buggies (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - City scene, horse cabby; Kay M. Wiest drawing, "Snafu Dock" (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - City street scene (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - American woman artist, various city scenes (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Kano market scene (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Native quarry work (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Two men with welcome to India sign (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - River scene, boats in dry dock (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Street scene, sphinx with pyramids (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Barrels (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Native group scenes, over view of town (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Men with guns, street scene, river and shoreline with boats (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Catholic cathedral, US airplane, street scene, beach scene (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Two Algerian men 1945 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Boat in water, Freetown, Sierra Leone (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Marching band, river scene, Gold Coast palm trees and boat (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Road scene, mud building (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Eritrean man and boy (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Central Africa, begging boys (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Native chief (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Mule and native - North African desert (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - British soldiers group funeral, two African women (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Battlefield landscape (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Massawa seaport (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Seaside city street scene (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Boat dock, American Soldier, Indian female soldier (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Landscape with buildings, 45 miles east of Casablanca (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Nigerian hunter (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Unidentified street scene (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Clay effigy of Sir Afori Atta (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Governor's palace, East Africa (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Governor's palace gardens, East Africa (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Four women with children, native boat on river (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Native village street scene, North Africa (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Native village scene (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Edge of city scene with horse and wagon (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Native group scene, building courtyard scene (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Two young native girls (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Africans excavating (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Native woman nursing child (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Young native woman (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Idlewylde camp, mosque (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Portraits of native men, large tortoises with Capt. Chambers (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - City outskirts (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Native men with machetes and knives (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Native family, Woven Wall, North Africa (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - City street scene, North Africa (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Street scene, mud buildings (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Building in North African city (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Americans and Africans with Buick (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Young native woman posing (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - President Roosevelt and Liberian President Barclay eating meal with others, music classroom, building (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Soldier with native children (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Boat with Africans, execution, cremation, mosque, camel (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Street scene with mosque (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Boy playing musical instrument on boat "Sudan" (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Egyptian statue, navy barber (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Duck and Guinea hunt in Maidirgini (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Child (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Native women, Gold Coast (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Akyea Mensah, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Soldier with machine gun, two African men (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Cape Palmas, Liberia (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Three snails, short hand, Malaria control, rock formation, street scene (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Transport convoy, Mosque, Parker House Roll (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Christianburg Castle, beach photo, Gold Coast (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Italian-built highway, Massawa to Asmara (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Nile River scene, Egypt (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Arab in Casablanca (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - American teaching arms to Liberians (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Group of native women, pyramids (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Native women, sphinx, paradise, two men (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Plane on fire, landing strip, native scenes (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Landscape scenes, misc. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - North African city street scene (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - City skyline, Africa (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Two postcards, boats on beach, native women (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Soldier on bike, soldier on board, boarding ship, deity sculpture, native woman (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Military transport, men bowling, Christian church, street scene (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - G.I. show, painted 'Belles' women (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - G.I. show, British entrance (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - G.I. show, city scenes, cobra charmer, women in front of health center sign (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Large bonfire, strange native woman, deity sculpture (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Three misc. photos, horse taxi, soldier bath, tree-lined street (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Desert landscapes (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Soldiers at attention, two landscapes, soldiers boarding plane (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Soldier skinning cow, outpost buildings (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Native street scene, marker, US winter family photos (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - US family scenes, photos (non-African) (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Native village, huts, US family photos (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Native boys with bowls, beggars, Central Africa (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Ant hill, 15 feet high, Liberia (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Two men on street, North Africa (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - goat postcard, river aerial photo, Barber giving chimp haircut, early pyramids, painted native women (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Men hoisting sail on boat, African marching band, beach with boats, soldiers on horses, ox powering pump (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Goats drinking water, old buildings, group of native women with one man, execution photo, pyramid, health center (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Native woman posing, bonfire, road-bridge, pyramid (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Ditch digging (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Mosque, North Africa (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Church (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Military training, tent, town street scene (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Moslem feast celebration (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Ceylon (?) street scene (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Native boats in port, Accra Harbor, Gold Coast, BWA (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Two children in front of small sphinx, military dental treatment (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Sphinx (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Integrated officers training school, Monrovia, Liberia (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Black and white American military training instructors, Monrovia, Liberia (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Black and white workers, propellors (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Three painted boys (snake society), Asmara images (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - President Roosevelt with President Barclay in jeep (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Roosevelt with Barclay at a meal (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Roosevelt with Barclay at a meal, landscape photos, North Africa (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Roosevelt with Harry Hopkins at a meal (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Roosevelt inspecting troops, city street scene (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Firestone plantation village (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Firestone plantation golf course (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Firestone plantation village, rail car filling place (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Firestone native village scene, young woman with child (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Native huts, Firestone plantation (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Firestone rubber factory, Liberia (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Firestone rubber plantation (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Two musicians, Firestone rubber tree, street scenes (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Mountain road scenes (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Gold Coast palm trees and boat (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - River scene (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Mountain scene (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Bull, cattle grazing, city street scene, three landscape photos, woman with child (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Mountain and beach scenes, aerial photo (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Coptic monastery, Nefasit, Eritrea (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Nile River, aerial photo (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Malaria warning poster (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Chiggers on native toes (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - US doctor taking blood sample from native woman (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Army doctors treating native girl with malaria (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Vaginal "social" diseases (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Vultures and dog, ship repair in Massawa (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Native women anatomy (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Native woman with skin disorder, four various medical treatments (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Sgt. with two monkeys, painted native woman, boy with bulging cheek, army boat in river, mosque (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Elephantiasis of the scrotum (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Native woman with filariasis of the breast (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Enlarged scrotum warning, Coptic church, Asmara scenes (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Removed enlarged scrotum from surgery, three chimpanzee postcards made in St. Louis (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Removing scrotum from native with elephantiasis (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Native woman with filariasis of the breast (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Billy O chimp with pipe, scrotum removal operation (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Native with filariasis of the scrotum (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Enlarged scrotum, filariasis of breast (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Removed scrotum, 52 lbs. (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - US patrol squad; Africans with facial disfigurements; Young Mohammedan man, Central Africa; flag raising ceremony (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - US doctors treating native girl with malaria (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Medical operation, mosque, firetruck, crane (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Enlarged scrotum, filariasis (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Americans removing enlarged scrotum (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Scuttled Axis ship, malaria warning, enlarged scrotum (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Leper, chief (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Woman leper (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Woman dying of leprosy (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Native leper colony (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Four native anatomy photos (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - African bushmen (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Woman with steatopygia (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Steatopygia, pygmies (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Three women with fat disorder (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Wall built of cans, North Africa, execution photo (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Quonset style buildings, North Africa (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Storage tanks for oil or water (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - US Army Air Forces four-engine plane (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Accra harbor, Gold Coast (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Mosque (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Cape Palmas, Liberia (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Young Mohammedan man, Central Africa (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Landscape scene, 'This is Africa' (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Two men with welcome to India sign (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Unknown seaport scene (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Ox-driven irrigation postcard (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Soldier grave (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Ethiopian spinning cotton by hand (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Africans walking on road, photographs of Africans in groups (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Christianburg Castle, Accra (cannons) (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Gold Coast palm trees and boat (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - Cable car, Nefasit (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - Accra market scene (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Captured Italian cable car system, Massawa (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Loading military plane (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - Native dignitary, celebration (Box 2, Folder 131)
    - Instruction, PT boat, building entrance (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - Sphinx, two painted women, Billy O chimp (Box 2, Folder 133)
    - Casablanca raid article (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - US transport ship, fortress building (Box 2, Folder 135)
    - British building, patient taken from plane, native boats, group of Africans (Box 2, Folder 136)
    - Arab with camel, Parker House Roll (Box 2, Folder 137)
    - Asmara mosque (Box 2, Folder 138)
    - Train/locomotive, Eritrea to Massawa (Box 2, Folder 139)
    - Large tree (Box 2, Folder 140)
    - Eritrea orange grove (Box 2, Folder 141)
    - Eritrean boys (Box 2, Folder 142)
    - Railway/viaduct, Asmara to Massawa (Box 2, Folder 143)
    - Christianburg Castle, Gold Coast (Box 2, Folder 144)
    - "Atumpom" painting by Sam Smith (Box 2, Folder 145)
    - Kabba village drawing (Box 2, Folder 146)
    - Railway, mountains, Eritrea (Box 2, Folder 147)
    - Maiduguriblues poster, horizontal statue behind two men riding camels, street scene (Box 2, Folder 148)
    - Egyptian shirt salesman (Box 2, Folder 149)
    - Boat, ocean scene, 'Mountains in Eritrea' (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - Khartoum warehouse with guard (Box 2, Folder 151)
    - Painted native woman dancing (Box 2, Folder 152)
    - Native prostitutes, venereal disease camp (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - Native woman dancing inside Shangri-La compound (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - Gambling, painted African women (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - President Roosevelt reviews troops in North Africa (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - President Roosevelt and President Barclay shaking hands (Box 2, Folder 157)
    - Airplane refueling, four women with children (Box 2, Folder 158)
    - Airplane propeller work (Box 2, Folder 159)
    - Snake society Africans (Box 2, Folder 160)
    - US Soldiers collecting rubber sap, Firestone Plantation (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - Military airport(?), market scene, Doc and Billy O (Box 2, Folder 162)
    - Painted native women (Box 2, Folder 163)
    - Native women in uniforms, riverport, pile of fruit (Box 2, Folder 164)
    - GIs playing poker, mountain road scenes (Box 2, Folder 165)
    - Amphibious plane named 'Billy O' (Box 2, Folder 166)
    - Loading packages into airplane (Box 2, Folder 167)
    - Beach scene with surfboard (Box 2, Folder 168)
    - Americans capture eagle (Box 2, Folder 169)
    - Barracks, Parker House Roll (Box 2, Folder 170)
    - Soldier posing with grenade (Box 2, Folder 171)
    - Gutting a bull (Box 2, Folder 172)
    - Africans unloading poles, repair of ship, naval base, Massawa (Box 2, Folder 173)
    - Belles camp, landscapes, Parker House Roll (Box 2, Folder 174)
    - Military ships sleeping quarters, old mosque (Box 2, Folder 175)
    - Preparing bush cow for meat, Liberia (Box 2, Folder 176)
    - Actor with piano player, farming scenes, mosque, dining room (Box 2, Folder 177)
    - Twin engine military plane, execution photo, large building (Box 2, Folder 178)
    - American teaching native, bayonet practice (Box 2, Folder 179)
    - Military setup, enlarged scrotum, rubber tree drawing (Box 2, Folder 180)
    - Two soldiers with native in canoe (Box 2, Folder 181)
    - Red Cross truck with workers (Box 2, Folder 182)
    - Camp at sundown, Liberia (Box 2, Folder 183)
    - Military meal with priest (Box 2, Folder 184)
    - Mess hall, mountain scene (Box 2, Folder 185)
    - Africans gambling on US airfield (Box 2, Folder 186)
    - US Army baseball game (Box 2, Folder 187-188)
    - British military burial, landscape, dignitaries, native blacksmith (Box 2, Folder 189)
    - Military life, misc. (Box 2, Folder 190)
    - US Task Force Building, street scene, US classroom, landscape, mosque (Box 2, Folder 191)
    - Soldiers dressed as women, two men with welcome to India sign, groups of Africans (Box 2, Folder 192)
    - Enlisted man's club, Kay M. Wiest (Box 2, Folder 193)
    - Shipside drill, street scene (Box 2, Folder 194)
    - Airplane repair (note names on side of plane) (Box 2, Folder 195)
    - US Army Air Corps, Maiduguri, Nigeria (Box 2, Folder 196)
    - Military flag raising (Box 2, Folder 197)
    - Full company (Task Force 5889), moving patient from plane, WACS, native boys, mud building (Box 2, Folder 198)
    - Military flag raising (Box 2, Folder 199)
    - Sgt. Huffstatler at German consulate, West Africa (Box 2, Folder 200)
    - Three children, road map - Liberia (Box 2, Folder 201)
    - Black US soldiers getting off boat, monkey, landscape, snake society (Box 2, Folder 202)
    - Black and white band members, African yearbook cover (Box 2, Folder 203)
    - US Mail Call, shower note to Katy (Box 2, Folder 204)